# **Judson James**

https://judsonjames.com • judsonjames96@gmail.com

Full Stack Software Engineer with over four years of experience. Worked Full Time throughout college while obtaining his Computer Engineering degree. While working and managing course load, he also was recognized with Leadership Distinction in Public and Civic Engagement and a 3.4 GPA. Judson has experience in fields such as HIPAA, Government Contracting, Data Science, Full Stack DevOps, Load Testing, and Open Source software development.

## **TECHNICAL SKILLS SUMMARY**

- Programming: JavaScript / TypeScript , Python, Go, Rust, Java, C/C++, C#, Dart,
- Technologies: Actix, API Gateway, Athena, Cognito, Diesel, Django, DigitalOcean, Docker, Elastic Beanstalk, Express, Falcon, Firebase, Flask, Flutter, GatsbyJS, GraphQL, K6, Lambda, Material UI, Mongo, Netlify, NextJS, Nginx, Node.js, PostgreSQL, React, Relay, REST, Rocket, Selenium, Serverless, S3
- DevOps: Docker/Kubernetes, Kanban/Agile, AWS, Git, Peer Review, Architecture Management, Figma/LucidChart
- Web application development using Python, JavaScript, Go, and Rust applications (SPA, Universal, or Static)
- Project Management and Software Life-Cycle management with GitHub, GitLab, and Jira including PR
- Experienced with mono-repos that utilize multi-language and multi-platform solutions for clients
- Skilled in path-finding algorithms, robotic algorithms, and machine learning
- Strong verbal communication skills from instructing students, managing junior developers

#### PROFESSIONAL WORK EXPERIENCE

Pavcon LLC Fully Remote from Lexington, KY

Nov 2020- Present

- Software Engineer: web/server/devops
- Managed and Developed several projects simultaneously for the United States Air Force
- Tech Stacks included Angular SPAs, Django or Node.js Serverless Backends with AWS Services
- Only Full Stack developer for one project, managed junior developers for others
- Worked closely with Project Managers and AF Personnel to provide accurate data with secure interfaces

# Trapp Technology Fully Remote from Lexington, KY

Aug 2020-Nov 2020

Software Developer: web/server applications

- Consistently work within a rapid paced Agile work environment to build web and server applications
- Collaborate and develop Go GraphQL server applications to be used by TypeScript React applications

#### **52inc** Columbia, SC

Jul 2019–Jul 2020

Software Developer: web/mobile/server applications

- Developed web and server applications using JavaScript and Python libraries
- Utilized custom webpack configurations for applications such as Microsoft Word and Google Docs
- Participated in code review for unit-testing and code linting

# Center for Digital Humanities Columbia, SC

Dec 2018-May 2019

Software Developer: server applications

• Developed web applications using Django/React and managed servers and unit tests

### Van Robotics, LLC Columbia, SC

May 2018-Nov 2018

Software Developer and Hardware Engineer

• Designed prototypes for Django web app that helps tutor fifth-grade students, built beta of hardware

# University of South Carolina Student Success Center Columbia, SC

Aug 2016-May 2019

Supplemental Instructor and Peer Leader

• Presented three weekly supplemental study sessions to develop concepts for students and enhance their understanding, hosting up to 50 Computer Science and Engineering students per session

## **EDUCATION**

University of South Carolina Columbia, SC

Bachelor of Science in Computer Engineering May 2019

Graduated with Leadership Distinction in Public and Civic Engagement GPA: 3.4